nutritionstudies.org 2019-04-27

# Privacy Policy - Center for Nutrition Studies

The T. Colin Campbell Center for Nutrition Studies (“CNS”) values the private information of visitors to our website (the “Site”) and understands the need for security surrounding such information. The following policies outline the ways in which we collect, store and use personally identifiable information in providing our services. It also explains our use of cookies and delineates our legal policy. Except for very limited exceptions we do not share any personally identifiable information with third parties. We reserve the right to modify, alter or otherwise update this Privacy Policy at any time and you are encouraged to periodically review it.

### Information Collected

For each use of the Site, information about you is collected such as your IP address, the website from which you are redirected to the Site or search query, the date and duration of your visit, your browser, operating system, your browsing activity on the Site and particularly the pages you visit on the Site. This information, some of which may be considered personally identifiable information, is only used for statistical purposes and to analyze and optimize the functioning and the use of our Site. To this end, CNS uses the services of third parties to which such information is communicated for these purposes. 

We also obtain personal data from you when you send or receive electronic communications with us such as as signing up for our newsletter, sending online donations or otherwise voluntarily providing us with personal information.

### Newsletters

If you wish to subscribe to our electronic newsletter(s) or receive other materials in electronic or print form, we will use your e-mail or mailing address, as applicable, to send the requested materials.

### Use of Collected Information

The information collected is used for the following purposes: to manage and improve our Site; to enable you to get involved in CNS activities; to allow you to receive information such as updates and newsletters on our activities to enable you to support CNS; to apply for a position of employment at CNS; and to respond to your inquiries, requests or communications. If you choose to provide your information to CNS, you may receive information from CNS about various projects and activities. 

### Legal Bases for Collecting and Using Information

A note here for those in the European Union about our legal grounds for processing information about you under EU data protection laws, which is that our use of your information is based on the grounds that:  
(1) The use is necessary in order to fulfill our commitments to you under our Terms of Service or other agreements with you or is necessary to administer your account–for example, in order to enable access to our website on your device; or  
(2) The use is necessary for compliance with a legal obligation; or  
(3) The use is necessary in order to protect your vital interests or those of another person; or  
(4) We have a legitimate interest in using your information–for example, to provide and update our Services, to improve our Services so that we can offer you an even better user experience, to safeguard our Services, to communicate with you, to measure, gauge, and improve the effectiveness of our advertising, and better understand user retention and attrition, to monitor and prevent any problems with our Services, and to personalize your experience; or  
(5) You have given us your consent–for example before we place certain cookies on your device and access and analyze them later on, as described below in our Cookies Policy.

### Disclosure of Information

We may employ third parties to perform functions on our behalf including, without limitation, administering components of this Site. We may share personal data with these third parties in order to provide these services. We make commercially reasonable efforts to confirm that these third parties are prohibited from using your personal data for any other purpose.

We may also share your personal data with CNS partner organizations, independent contractors and other entities and individuals to further CNS’s charitable purposes. We make commercially reasonable efforts to confirm that these third parties are prohibited from using your personal data for any other purpose.

We will not sell your personal data or any other information we collect about your activity on our Site.

We reserve the right to disclose your personal data information as required by law, when we believe that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights, to comply with a legal obligation or a request from governmental authorities conducting an investigation, to verify or enforce compliance with the policies governing the Site, or to protect the legal rights, interests, or safety of CNS, the Site, our users or others.

### Your Consent

By providing us with your personal data, you consent to the collection and use of this information in accordance with the purposes described in this Privacy Policy.

### International Transfers

By using the Site, you expressly acknowledge and agree that, in the framework of the processing of personal data, such information can be transferred to countries which do not offer a similar level of protection for personal data as your country of residence, and specifically to the United States.

### Links to Other Sites

This Site may contain links to other sites that are not owned or controlled by CNS. We are not responsible for the use of cookies or the privacy practices or content of such other sites. Please consult the linked sites’ respective terms of use for more information.

### How Do We Protect Personal Information

We take appropriate measures to ensure that the personal data you disclose to us is kept secure, accurate and up to date and is kept only for so long as is necessary for the purposes for which it is used.

### Right of Access, Modification and Rectification

You have a right of access, modification and rectification of your personal data, at any time and free of charge. Some of the functionalities of our Site, via third party providers, may enable you to manage and modify your account settings yourself and to choose to stop receiving emails from CNS. Similarly, you can oppose the processing of your personal data by [contacting us](https://nutritionstudies.org/about/contact/).

### Cookies Policy

Our Site uses several cookies. By using our Site, you agree that we may place these and other similar types of cookies on your device and access them when you visit the Site in the future. A cookie is a small file of letters and numbers that, with your agreement, we put on your computer. The cookies we use are primarily analytical cookies that aid us in improving both our Site and your experience by tracking which areas and features of our Site are popular, making the Site easier to navigate, and to count visits. We may also use cookies placed on our Site by third parties acting on our behalf.

If you want to delete these cookies or any other cookies that are already on your computer, please refer to the help and support areas on your internet browser for instructions on how to locate the file or directory that stores cookies.

Information on cookies, including deleting or controlling them, can be found at: [aboutcookies.org](http://www.aboutcookies.org/ "website") or at [allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/ "website"). Please note that, by deleting our cookies or disabling future cookies, you may not be able to access certain areas or features of our Site and the Site may not function properly.

### Enforcement

If you feel that our Site is not following the Privacy Policy outlined above, please [contact us](https://nutritionstudies.org/about/contact/). Alternatively, you can contact your state or local chapters of the Better Business Bureau, state or local consumer protection office, or the Federal Trade Commission at 202-FTC-HELP (202-382-4357).
